Impartial Chairman, Decisions. Coat and Suit Industry. 6036/015
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Impartial Chairman, Decisions. Coat and Suit Industry.
1924-1962
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Impartial Chairman of the Coat and Suit Industry
6036/015
4 cubic feet
4 linear ft.
Articles, reprints, pamphlets, correspondence, photographs.
This collection consists of decisions by the Impartial Chairman of the Coat and Suit Industry from 1924 to 1962, as well as some transcripts, memoranda, and other files related to hearings before the chairman.
5767581
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 30, 2011
EAD encoding:
Kathryn Dowgiewicz, January 10, 2013
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Scope and Contents
Important disputes in the garment industry were submitted to a permanent Board of Arbitration who would hand down final decisions. On January 24, 1914, the Board of Arbitration created a Committee on Immediate Action that consisted of chief clerks as well as an Impartial Chairman, whose job was to arbitrate all disputes that the clerks were unable to settle and supervise labor conditions. This collection contains the decisions of the Impartial Chairman of the Coat and Suit Industry in New York City. The collection consists of the bound summaries of decisions and complaints that came before the Impartial Chairman and include the case name, brief descriptions, and the board decision. The cases are individually numbered and arranged by year beginning in 1924 and ending in 1962. Also included is a complete transcript of a hearing. The bound decisions in the later years are particularly helpful as they contain an index for the cases according to subject. Through the years there were a number of Impartial Chairmen who are identified on the cases and include (along with the dates of their decisions in the collection): Raymond V. Ingersoll (1924-1931), George W. Alger (1932-1935), Sol A. Rosenblatt (1931-1962), James J. Walker (1940-1945), Harry L. Hopkins (1945-1946), and Charles Poletti (1946).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/081: ILGWU. Legal Department records 6036/017: Impartial Chairman, Decisions, Dress Industry NYC Harry Uviller.
Clothing trade -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Collective labor agreements -- Clothing industry -- New York (State) -- New York; Ingersoll, Raymond V.; Alger, George W. -- (George William), -- b.1872.; Rosenblatt, Sol A., -- b.1900.; Walker, James J.; Hopkins, Harry L.; Poletti, Charles.; Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers' Protective Association (New York, N.Y.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5767581
- Records of cases before Raymond Ingersoll, 1924-1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Bound volume
- Decisions by Raymond Ingersoll, 1924-1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Records of cases before George Alger and Sol Rosenblatt, 1932-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Decisions by George Alger, 1931-1935 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1935-1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Decisions by James Walker, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Decisions by James Walker and Harry Hopkins, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Memorandum submitted to Harry Hopkins, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Transcript of hearings before Charles Poletti, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Bound volume. May 4, 1947-May 31, 1948.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Bound volume. June 1, 1948-May 31, 1949.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Bound volume. June 1, 1949-May 31, 1950.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Bound volume. June 1, 1950-May 31, 1951.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Bound volume. June 1, 1951-May 31, 1952.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Bound volume. June 1, 1952-May 31, 1953.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Bound volume. June 1, 1953-May 31, 1954.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Bound volume, part 1. June 1, 1954-May 31, 1955.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Bound volume, part 2. June 1, 1954-May 31, 1955.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Bound volume, part 1. June 1, 1955-May 31, 1956.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Bound volume, part 2. June 1, 1955-May 31, 1956.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Bound volume. June 1, 1956-May 31, 1957.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Bound volume. June 1, 1957-May 31, 1958.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Bound volume. June 1, 1958-May 31, 1959.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Bound volume. June 1, 1959-May 31, 1960.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Bound volume. June 1, 1960-May 31, 1961.
- Decisions by Sol Rosenblatt, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Bound volume. June 1, 1961-May 31, 1962.